Curriculum Vitae



DHARMENDRA SHISHODIY

Address: - H.No- 494 Sihani road Vishwas Nagar,

Opp Zila Sehkari Bank, Ghaziabad-

201001 (Uttar Pradesh)

Email-dshishodiya88@gmail.com

Phone # 7503929105

Overview

An enthusiastic National Supply Chain/Logistics & Operations Professional with almost Fifteen Years of Experience Filled with drive, determination and ability to oversee the efficient Supply chainn/Logistics & Operations, Team Management and Dealer & Distribution Network of Pan India. Having the necessary management skills required to administer, improve and develop a Supply Chain/Logistics & Operation Strategy to achieve maximum efficiency, effectiveness and quality of Organisation. Currently looking for a position that offers variety and the opportunity to develop both personally and professionally.

Key Skills & Core Competencies

- Distribution Centre-Team Handling-Management-Retail-Project Industry
- Logistics Management- Supply Chain Management-Safety Procedures-Warehouse Management-Inventory
- Management/Hygiene-Material Requirement Planning & Distribution Requirement Planning-Logistics Operations-W/H Operation-Vendor Management-Order Management-Billing Management-
- Material Management -Organizing Shipments -Strong Execution-SAP SD &MM Module-Sales Support-
- Import and Export Transportation Management-Demand Planning-Forecast-CFA agents Handling-5s Norms
 ERP-Fleet Management- Troubleshooting Skills-3P Contractors- Manpower Management
 Warehousing dealing Maintenance/MHE Management

CAREER HISTORY:-

Company – AVENUE SUPERMARTS LTD (D-MART)–MUMBAI

Job Profile – Head – Distribution Centre Operations

Heading Locations-- Isnapur DC (4.5 L Sqft) & Yellampet DC (2.5 L sqft) & Patancheru

Import DC (80k Sqft) Hyderabad

Heading Distribution States - (Southern & Northern Region)
Period - (Jan 2022 Onwards.)

Industry - Retail / Garments / GM / FMCG / Food - Non Food / Core - Non Core

- Handling the Annum Business of 2800Cr & Daily 350 Container Transactions including Inward & Outward.
- Responsible for Managing the Team of 1650 Persons (Including 250 On Role Staff) Including 75 Managers with various Departments like –

Facility/Receiving/Grn/Hygiene/Purchase/Loading/PGI/Picking/Maintennance/HR/Accounts/Transport/Category/3P Vendors/Payroll Vendors etc.

Responsible for timely supply for 160 Dmart Stores in Southern & Northern Regions

Roles & Responsibilities as a DCM-

- 1.Daily DC's Premises Inside & Outside Walk and Ensure Hygiene & Cleanliness.
- 2.Ensuring Daily Breifing With all DC's Departments
- 3. Checking Daily Manpower & Attendance Registers
- 4. Spending Time with Asst. Managers & ADCM
- 5.Daily check GRN vs STN Report & Monthly report
- 6. Routing Check of Excess stock and unaccountable inventory
- 7. Daily check & Visit the Loading & Unloading docks with Putaway area
- 8.Daily check Maintenance AC/Forklift/BOPT/EHPT/Stacker/DG/Fire Pump Room
- 9. Daily Follow up on Pending works of all Internal departments
- 10. Daily ensuring Vendor debit collection & Regular dispatches
- 11. Daily Vendor Payment releasing
- 12. Drop mail to category team if any issues pending
- 13. Taken daily follow up for PNM status
- 14. Ensuring daily Safety aspect and discipiline
- 15. Arrange weekly Meeting & Reviews with all departments
- 16. Taken follow up of on every week Vendor Debit stock
- 17. Daily checking MRM report & participating every month inn MRM Meetings.
- 18. Checking contra/short/excess/case lot stock file with concern department manager
- 19. Regular check up of slow moving SKU & CBFT file.
- 20.Daily update on Store issues like MB5T & Rev MB5T Damage & write of Data
- 21. Daily check MIS data & FIFO check
- 22. Staff Salaries & 3P Salaries update status on Every Salary Cycle

- 23. Monthly rent ,warai & Maintenance related check
- 24. Check & approving monthly roasters of all Departments.
- 25.Ensuring daily DC's Operations run smoothly & Plan Surprising Visit in Night shift.

CAREER HISTORY:-

Company - CERA SANITARYWARE LTD - HYDERABAD

Job Profile – Commercial Operations

Warehouse Operations /Logistics/Supply Chain

State - (A.P & T.G)

Period - (Jan 2021-Dec 2021.)

Industry – Ceramics/Sanitaryware/Hardware

Responsible for planning out all Warehouse resources & activities in relation to companies objectives & targets. Also keeping track of stock using computer systems, allocating space for storing goods & organizing special requirements for stock.

- Managing Inbound and Outbound Logistics.
- Managing the transportation.
- Handling the Cargo/Couriers and ensure to get the material delivery as per TAT.
- Monthly warehouse stock audit and ensure to resolves all inventory related issues weekly or 15 days behalf.
- Ensure to achieve monthly targets.
- Pending Orders review on Daily basis for Both State & Follow up with depot/factory and sales team for the execution.
- ♣ Arrange the "Daily Billing Plan" from the respective factory and depots and submit the same to corporate office and ensure its fulfilment by EOD.
- Inventory Management, Warehouse Operations, Warehouse Management & Supply Chain Management.
- Vendor management, Materials Planning from vendor considering the minimum and maximum level in each factory and depot.
- Proper adherence of timely completion of Sales returns.
- Coordinate and ensure physical verification are done on monthly basis to ensure to Zero variance.
- Involved in meeting with area sales managers and ensure stocks are available in right locations at the right time.
- Make a simple Route Plan with transporter to deliver the materials for next day planning.
- Track the in-transit delays and take corrective action for their closure.
- ♣ Monthly review of materials supply against the sales plan and sales forecast and provide the same to concern vendor for materials planning.
- Follow up with transporters for material delivery as per TAT and information to all concerns.
- Verify the Transports freight bills and loading and unloading bills by transporters for further payment process.
- Ensure Zero- variance (matching) of System Vs Physical stock as per records.
- Optimize the freight cost and work on target saving freight cost.
- **♣** Ensure efficient and cost-effective operation and optimize space utilization.
- Move the material in respective location (Both physically as well as in System) if any damage or other issues in materials.

- ♣ Monthly dealer visits and take the feedback from the dealers on the dealer's feedback form and send it concern department mark a copy in CC to the management for the issue resolve.
- Report preparation, analysis and presentation to management at weekly and monthly.

Company - CERA SANITARYWARE LTD

Job Profile - Warehouse Manager /Logistics/Supply Chain

State - (Delhi & U.P)

Period - (July 2012 - Dec 2020).

Industry – Ceramics/Sanitarywares/Hardwares

Handling warehouse of overall approx 80k Square Feet of North region of Delhi & Ghaziabad (approx 80k Square Feet) Additional industry Knowledge like FMCG, Home & Bath Solutions, Luggage (Suitcase), Automobile, Paints & Tiles.

- Inventory Management
- Goods Received notes
- Logistic and supply chain management
- Stock Verification
- Maintain of Records
- Goods Return process follows as per co. norms.
- Daily Warehouse Report update to related Concern.
- ❖ Handling Dealer or vendor Debit and Credit notes issue.
- Solving customers/Dealers queries
- Maintaining & Updating Inventory reports
- Reporting of GRN goods to H.O.
- Manage Purchase order of Clients and update pendency .
- Appropriate manpower planning and deployment
- Coordination with Transport Department for Daily dispatch & Arrangement of vehicles on self basis for urgent dispatch.
- Doing survey Claims of Transit material as per survey policy.
- Duties: Managing all processes and functions within a busy warehouse.
- Managing a team of up to 20 employees within the warehouse.
- Coordinating racking and storing. Maintaining high standards of materials handling.
- Responsible for the warehouse security and accountability.
- Ensuring stock levels are managed and controlled effectively.
- Ensuring compliance with all Health and Safety regulations.
- Using automated computer systems to monitor stock control.
- Implementing new projects. Producing incident and performance reports for senior managers.
- Making sure that all freight receipts and deliveries are carried out in time.
- Scheduling work & rotas to meet fluctuations in staffing levels & workloads.
- Leading, motivating, training and developing staff.
- Visiting clients to monitor the quality of service they are receiving.
- Updating & maintaining computerized & paper based administrative records.
- * Responsible for the disciplinary & grievance procedures.
- Working with team leaders to review procedures & maximize customer satisfaction.

Company - CERA SANITARYWARE LTD -

Job Profile - Warehouse In-Charge/Logistics/Supply Chain

State - (U.P)

Period - (Jan 2009 - July 2012).

Industry – Sanitary/Bathware/Faucet

- Manage, oversee, supervise and participate in Warehouse operations.
- Approve requisitions, analyzes work orders, etc. To manage the warehouse in terms
- > of receipts and Issues of Material and its safe storage/handling. To ensure safety,
- Environmental protection and security of men and materials. Dispatch of Goods with proper documentation.
- To streamline the Warehouse and Stores administration. To define Standard Operating Procedures for each Warehousing location & to constantly monitor and measure administrative services. Responsible for perpetual stock taking of Warehouse items, correctness of issues and receipt accounting.
- Online stocks available from system using Base one and managing a team of 5 people Rejected items and returnable items are reviewed on a regular basis.
- To manage the warehouse in terms of receipts and Issues of RM and its safe Storage/handling. To ensure safety, environmental protection and security of men and materials
- Ensure FIFO, Segregated storage as per plan And ensuring availability of trucks for dispatch & Coordination with Transport department .Ensure proper documentation, record keeping, check list maintenance And MIS reporting. Brief staff on materials to be loaded or on assembly of items to Be delivered.
- Check with staff for changes that could affect delivery schedule; Make schedule adjustments as needed. Review paperwork from deliveries to Determine if additional work requirements will occur. Check documents for Thoroughness and completeness and prepare additional documentation when Necessary.
- Check All the Rejected or Damage Material and doing the Survey Claim on as per policy basis.
- Maintaining the inventory level as per Warehouse Areas and Bulk Requirement.

Company - CERA SANITARYWARE LTD

Job Profile – Store Keeper /Logistics/Supply Chain

State - (U.P)

Period - (May 2008 - Dec 2008).

Industry-Tiles

- ✓ Responsible for organizing the warehouse areas, making the best and most efficient use of space, and managing the day to day activities of warehouse operations.
- ✓ Taking physical inventories of stock and reconciling variances. Overseeing all Picking, packing and distribution activity. Ensuring delivery vehicle and driver compliance with all applicable rules, policies, laws and regulations.
- ✓ Maintaining the all activities in the Warehouse area .Ensure proper documentation, record keeping, check list maintenance and MIS reporting.
- ✓ Brief staff on materials to be loaded or on assembly of items to be delivered. Check with staff for changes that could affect delivery schedule, make schedule adjustments as needed. Review paperwork from deliveries to determine if additional work requirements will occur. Check documents for thoroughness and completeness and prepare additional documentation when necessary. Initiate all requests for replenishment of stock
- ✓ Oversee the receipt and dispersal of materials entering or leaving warehouse; help storekeepers with this task when required .Take periodic inventories and participate in Twice in a month inventory program. Supervise and coordinate the unloading of inbound

- shipments. Orderly stacking of product and the picking and staging of outbound shipments. Coordination with transporters as per daily schedule.
- ✓ Ensure total adherence to all Federal statutes regarding warehouse operations including Rules and regulations .Confer with department heads to ensure coordination of warehouse
- ✓ Activities such as production, sales, Promotion and purchasing.

Company - Sherwin Williams Paint India Ltd

Job Profile - Store Keeper/Logistics/Supply Chain

State - (U.P)

Period - (May 2007 - April 2008.)

Industry - Paints

Taking physical inventories of stock and reconciling variances. Overseeing all Picking, packing and distribution activity. Ensuring delivery vehicle and driver compliance with all applicable rules, policies, laws and regulations.

- Activities such as production, sales, and purchasing.
- Handling all Colors Shades Tinting and Shading by systems.
- Taken order and follow by sales channel.

Academic Qualifications:-

Class X - N.S.M.V.K School GZB From 2004-2005 58.80%

Class XII - Shri B.L Inter College Hathras From 2008-2009 with Science Stream 58.80%

Bachelor of Computer Application -Adhunik Group of Institution. GZB, C.C.S University Meerut From 2010-2012 First Div. **60.04**%

Certification :-

Post Graduate Diploma Supply Chain Management NMIMS MUMBAI with Distance Learning From 2018-2020 . **6.33**

Personal Details:-

Contact Address :H.No. 494, Vishwas Nagar, NH-58, Ghaziabad -201001

Date of Birth :Dec, 08, 1988

Father,s Name : Shri Vijay Singh

Language Proficiency: Hindi and English

Nationality : Indian

Hobbies & Interest : Photography , Cricket, Travelling, Music , Helping Each Other

References : Available on request.

22 Nov 2022

Hyderabad (Dharmendra)